<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Tom Leverstone - Projects</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://leverstone.me/projects/atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2025-03-15T00:24:10+00:00</updated><entry><title>Tech book club</title><link href="/projects/tech-book-club" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-15T00:24:10+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Leverstone</name></author><id>tag:None,2025-03-15:/projects/tech-book-club</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Reading technical books and discussing them over a mailing list&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm running a technical book club, over a mailing list. 📚✉️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's aimed at software engineers who want to improve their technical skills by reading and discussing what they read with a small, friendly, and easy to navigate community. It runs completely online, in the form of a mailing list. Every week there will be a thread to discuss the content we covered that week. There are no in-person aspect to this book club, and all communication is completely asynchronous. We will focus on one book at a time, and try to go through it over a few months. When we start a new book the agenda for the next few months will be published on the mailing list. Come join us!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Projects"></category></entry><entry><title>nagasaki45 / IDMT?</title><link href="/projects/nagasaki45-idmt" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-04-06T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-03-15T00:24:10+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Leverstone</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-04-06:/projects/nagasaki45-idmt</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Improvised, polymetric, modular, avant-pop, mess&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;nagasaki45 is my electronic music stage name. I improvise live sets
focusing on percussive, up-beat, and polymetric structures on a modular
synth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="idmt"&gt;IDMT?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lizzie Wilson, AKA &lt;a href="https://lwlsn.github.io/digitalselves-web/"&gt;digital
selves&lt;/a&gt;, is a London based
audiovisual artist who likes to use computer code to make sounds and
visuals and occasionally both. Together we play under the IDMT? alias.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Projects"></category></entry><entry><title>bibo</title><link href="/projects/bibo" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-04-06T02:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-03-15T00:24:10+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Leverstone</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-04-06:/projects/bibo</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Command line reference manager with a single source of truth: the .bib file. Inspired by beets.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;bibo is a command line reference manager with a single source of truth:
the .bib file. It is inspired by &lt;a href="https://beets.readthedocs.io/"&gt;beets&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It gives you control over your files. They are not hidden in some
    obscure database, hence easy to backup, share, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's a thin editor of .bib files, so no need to export your
    bibliography anywhere.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's extensible with plugins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's a command line tool. What not to ❤️?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out all the nitty gritty details on
&lt;a href="https://github.com/Nagasaki45/bibo"&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Projects"></category></entry><entry><title>Proker</title><link href="/projects/proker" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-15T00:24:10+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Leverstone</name></author><id>tag:None,2025-03-15:/projects/proker</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Web app for development teams to vote on... whatever&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Developers have many things to vote on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What to eat for lunch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Favourite colour scheme for the new website&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Estimated complexity of user stories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use Proker for any of these, but it's mostly made to help with the last point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've made this project for two reasons. First, I wanted to play a bit more with &lt;a href="https://hexdocs.pm/phoenix_live_view/welcome.html"&gt;Phoenix LiveView&lt;/a&gt; - an extension for the Elixir web framework Phoenix that provides SPA-like experience without writing any frontend code. Second, my team hated the web app we used to vote on user stories because rooms didn't work well (people dropping out and back in) and it was just very buggy. Proker has been serving us very well over the past 3 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cover image was made with &lt;a href="https://drawfast.tldraw.com/"&gt;tldraw's draw-fast&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Projects"></category></entry><entry><title>An Audio-Only Augmented Reality System for Social Interaction</title><link href="/projects/an-audio-only-augmented-reality-system-for-social-interaction" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-12-31T10:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-15T00:24:10+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Leverstone</name></author><id>tag:None,2015-12-31:/projects/an-audio-only-augmented-reality-system-for-social-interaction</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Master thesis in Music Technology, Bar-Ilan Music Department&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; Music plays a crucial role in social interactions. This
thesis examines how an interactive environment might facilitate such
exchanges by developing and evaluating a novel system for joint music
consumption by a group of users in the same place and time. The system
provides a platform for the creation of spatial interactive music. It
uses relative locations measured using a Bluetooth signal, and generates
an immersive personalized augmented musical environment that depends on
the location of its participants. I conducted two experiments testing
the system within the context of a silent disco party, using the
system's relative position signals as well as video tracking to
evaluate the experience of users with and without prior acquaintance.
The results showed that for both groups, the system promoted openness
and increased the social interaction between users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gurion, Tom. "An Audio-Only Augmented Reality System for Social
Interaction." Thesis. Bar-Ilan University Music Department. Ramat Gan
Israel, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id="publications"&gt;Publications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the thesis I published an extended abstract in the
proceedings of &lt;a href="http://hcii2013.org/"&gt;HCI International 2013&lt;/a&gt;, and
presented a &lt;a href="/pdfs/HCI2013%20poster.pdf"&gt;poster&lt;/a&gt; in the conference
posters session:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007%2F978-3-642-39473-7_65"&gt;Gurion, Tom, and Nori Jacoby. "Audio-only augmented reality system
for social interaction." HCI International 2013-Posters' Extended
Abstracts. Springer Berlin Heidelberg, 2013.
322-326.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The extended abstract PDF is freely available
&lt;a href="/pdfs/Gurion%20and%20Jacoby%20-%20Audio-Only%20Augmented%20Reality%20System%20for%20Social%20Interaction.pdf"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also gave an &lt;a href="http://www.slideshare.net/Nagasaki45/audioonly-augmented-reality-system-for-social-interaction"&gt;oral
presentation&lt;/a&gt;
of my research at &lt;a href="http://sites.ieee.org/istas-2013/"&gt;ISTAS'13&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="video-demonstration-of-the-pure-data-patch"&gt;Video demonstration of the Pure Data patch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This demo shows how movement of participants in space affects the music
they hear through their own Android device and headphones using the
system in a silent disco party. In addition it demonstrate the influence
of different participants on one another when one virtual participant
takes diverse sound zones with him during this simulation. The music is
the same as in the original system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="youtube youtube-16x9"&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2kJoeD2iWBA" allowfullscreen seamless frameBorder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Projects"></category></entry><entry><title>OS GR</title><link href="/projects/os-gr" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-05-24T17:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-03-15T00:24:10+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Leverstone</name></author><id>tag:None,2021-05-24:/projects/os-gr</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Android app to convert to and from OS grid reference.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Ordnance Survey grid reference is a British system to denote
geographic locations, similar to latitude and longitude. It is commonly
used in maps and guides for navigation. Many android apps, however,
don't work natively with OS grid references. This is where the &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.os_gr"&gt;OS GR
android app&lt;/a&gt;
comes in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can open a location from a different app with it, and it will tell
you the OS GR, or you can type one in and open it in a different app.
There are many apps that can tell you the GR of your location, based on
GPS, but IMHO it is more useful to be able to point at a location on a
map and ask for the GR. Annoyingly, not all maps / navigation apps
support opening a location in a different app (i.e. google maps and
komoot), so you cannot get the GR from these. You can still type in a GR
and open it in komoot for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="OS GR screenshots" src="/images/portfolio/os_gr_screenshots.webp"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="wanna-help"&gt;Wanna help?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have an android device, hence why it's an android app. It should
    be relatively easy to build an iOS app from the same source code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you're willing to contribute a better logo than the horrendous
    thing I've designed that will be great.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any comments, feature requests (within reason), please do tell.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get in touch either by email or on the &lt;a href="https://github.com/Nagasaki45/OS_GR"&gt;project's repo on
github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="disclaimer"&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I'm not a professional mobile developer, and it's just a free and
open source mini project of mine. It probably won't light your phone on
fire, or share your bank details with facebook, but it might (and
probably will) brake in unexpected ways. Please don't blindly rely on
this for navigation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Projects"></category></entry><entry><title>Unsocial VR</title><link href="/projects/unsocial-vr" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-14T10:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-03-15T00:24:10+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Leverstone</name></author><id>tag:None,2017-07-14:/projects/unsocial-vr</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fake social behaviours in shared virtual environment&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Advance Project Placement, Media and Arts Technology doctoral programme,
Queen Mary University of London. Supervised by Prof. Patrick Healey and
hosted by &lt;a href="https://www.inition.co.uk/"&gt;Inition&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="youtube youtube-16x9"&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tqbtOL5R4fw" allowfullscreen seamless frameBorder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id="what"&gt;What?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Infinite Jest, David Foster Wallace argues that &lt;em&gt;"Good old
traditional audio-only phone conversations allowed you to presume that
the person on the other end was paying complete attention to you while
also permitting you not to have to pay anything even close to complete
attention to her."&lt;/em&gt; He continues and claims that we are addicted to
this illusion, and that's why video conferencing always feel so
awkward - we need to pretend to listen all the time. And if we think
about it, even in face to face conversation we must always adhere to
these social rules, and signal our complete attention when someone is
talking to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this project I experiment with VR technologies to see if this
illusion of faking active listening is transferable to other mediums,
and if so, how. In Unsocial VR participants share the same virtual
environment, using the HTC Vive headset and controllers. They can
converse freely and move around, and if you want to start faking
listening to the conversation and just wander around, or even talk with
other participants while faking, you absolutely can! The interface is
very minimal, just hit a button on the controller to start faking active
listening behaviours towards your current conversation, and release it
when you want to stop faking. You will even get an on screen
notification when someone is speaking directly to you, so you can return
to the conversation elegantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project is based on multidisciplinary research. It merges ideas
from telepresence and mediated communication, that explore ways to
represent non verbal cues in new communication technologies. It depends
on multiparty social interaction analysis, which take spatial cues into
account in understanding who is talking with whom in a "cocktail
party" situation. It explores new ways to generate active listening
signals (or "backchannel behaviours", as they called in the scientific
literature), such as head nods, in automated agents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further information can be found in my
&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/K39_wlQ60-Y"&gt;mid-project&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/2k8MO74guTA"&gt;inter/sections&lt;/a&gt; presentations.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Projects"></category></entry><entry><title>The Krihelinator</title><link href="/projects/the-krihelinator" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-17T22:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-03-15T00:24:10+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Leverstone</name></author><id>tag:None,2016-10-17:/projects/the-krihelinator</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;"Trendiness of OSS should be assessed by contribution rate, not by stars" - Meir Kriheli&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This project proposes an alternative to &lt;a href="https://github.com/trending"&gt;github's trending
page&lt;/a&gt;, by exposing projects with high
contribution rate, instead of daily stars (similarly to github's pulse
page). The krihelimeter of each repository is calculated using the
number of authors, commits, pull requests, and issues of that project,
from the past week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="public-appearance"&gt;Public appearance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In March 2017, Wikipedia added the project to the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Measuring_programming_language_popularity"&gt;list project that
    measure programming language
    popularity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In January 2017 the project was introduced to &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=13450554"&gt;hacker
    news&lt;/a&gt;,
    &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/5pcylf/this_project_proposes_an_alternative_to_githubs/"&gt;reddit&lt;/a&gt;,
    and
    &lt;a href="https://lobste.rs/s/nlghvo/krihelinator_github_trending"&gt;lobsters&lt;/a&gt;,
    reaching the first page in each of them. This resulted in
    significant public interest, important feedback, and suggestions for
    improvements, as well as mentioning in the technology podcast
    &lt;a href="http://www.reversim.com/2017/02/315-bumpers-36.html"&gt;reversim&lt;/a&gt; (in
    Hebrew).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In August 2016 I presented the project in PyWeb IL. Here are the
    &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=03c_yQZKopY"&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; of my
    presentation (in Hebrew) and the
    &lt;a href="https://rawgit.com/Nagasaki45/pyweb-talk/master/index.html"&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In July 2016 &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/99hirARuiyY?t=31m53s"&gt;Shai Efrati presented the project in EuroPython
    lightening talks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="contribution"&gt;Contribution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an &lt;a href="https://github.com/Nagasaki45/krihelinator"&gt;open source
project&lt;/a&gt; under active
development. Your ideas and contribution are more than welcome!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Projects"></category></entry><entry><title>Malinka</title><link href="/projects/malinka" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-12-31T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-15T00:24:10+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Leverstone</name></author><id>tag:None,2015-12-31:/projects/malinka</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My indie-rock band, lead by Stav German&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Malinka is an independent rock band formed in Tel-Aviv. The songs stand
on the border of fantasy and the local reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stav German - music and vocals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Erez Dascal - guitar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tom Gurion - bass guitar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Barak Cohen - drums&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class="youtube youtube-16x9"&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SgISW_uyjjU" allowfullscreen seamless frameBorder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="youtube youtube-16x9"&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fzQoYdzAFz0" allowfullscreen seamless frameBorder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Projects"></category></entry><entry><title>Schleikess</title><link href="/projects/schleikess" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-24T12:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-03-15T00:24:10+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Leverstone</name></author><id>tag:None,2017-07-24:/projects/schleikess</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;"suspenders" in Yiddish&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A controller for full-body interactive performances that requires
applying force and effort to play with, hopefully facilitating
expressiveness. It is composed of two elastic bands that are attached to
the players' belt loops, and a main unit that measures the tension on
each elastic band. The player holds the other side of each elastic band
and stretches them to play. The controller is demonstrated using a
generative drum machine by mapping the stretch of the bands to tempo and
the pitch of the samples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="youtube youtube-16x9"&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_BUf_VLCIWQ" allowfullscreen seamless frameBorder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Projects"></category></entry><entry><title>tapeless cassettes</title><link href="/projects/tapeless-cassettes" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-14T11:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-15T00:24:10+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Leverstone</name></author><id>tag:None,2016-11-14:/projects/tapeless-cassettes</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Turn the wheels manually with your pinky or a BIC® pen to play the cassettes; the higher the speed the faster the music.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A CruftFest 2016 project / an assignment to the Interactive Digital
Multimedia Techniques (ESC742P) module, Media and Arts Technology, Queen
Mary University of London.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project uses modified audio cassettes as controllers for an
interactive and collaborative musical interface. It invites users to
manually turn the cassettes wheels, with their pinky or a BIC® pen, to
control the speed of the music. The interaction is simple and
intuitive - the higher the speed of the wheel, the faster the music.
Multiple cassettes enable a group of users to play together, letting
each one to control different track in the music. The resulted sounds
fluctuate in speed and in pitch, and therefore cannot be synchronized.
The lack of synchronization, which is unusual in familiar music, suggest
different types of interactions with the musical materials and between
players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="youtube youtube-16x9"&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JZ3Z4X_d1iQ" allowfullscreen seamless frameBorder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Projects"></category></entry><entry><title>Sign-language</title><link href="/projects/sign-language" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-15T00:24:10+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Leverstone</name></author><id>tag:None,2016-03-05:/projects/sign-language</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A gesture to speech application&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A gesture to speech application that uses the
&lt;a href="http://www.leapmotion.com/"&gt;LeapMotion&lt;/a&gt; to track gestures, the
&lt;a href="http://www.wekinator.org/"&gt;WekiMini&lt;/a&gt; to analyze the gestures using
supervised machine learning algorithms, and a python web server for text
to speech conversion and web interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project was originally created in the Hack2Wear hackathon (2014),
together with Ilai Giloh and Mel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="youtube youtube-16x9"&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/x6i9gXS5VEQ" allowfullscreen seamless frameBorder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Projects"></category></entry><entry><title>MusiGali</title><link href="/projects/musigali" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-01-10T23:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-15T00:24:10+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Leverstone</name></author><id>tag:None,2016-01-10:/projects/musigali</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;EEG controlled music for Brain Tech Israel 2013&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A project by Giori Politi, Sharon Duek, Jonathan Abramson and myself
which was developed / composed especially for the &lt;a href="http://conference.israelbrain.org/2013/"&gt;Brain Tech Israel
2013&lt;/a&gt; conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this project we create a musical soundtrack based on mind waves
transmitted from an EEG headset. The generated musical line is
parameterized according to levels of attention and meditation of the
headset wearer, leading the listener to unexpected musical realms which
somewhat correspond to his or her neuro-electric activity. One may try
to attain control over the musical line and advance within it through
deliberate control over levels of relaxation and concentration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The EEG headset we use for the project is &lt;a href="http://neurosky.com/biosensors/eeg-sensor/biosensors/"&gt;NueroSky MindWave
mobile&lt;/a&gt;. Music
was composed in &lt;a href="https://www.ableton.com/en/live/"&gt;Ableton Live&lt;/a&gt; using
&lt;a href="https://www.ableton.com/en/live/max-for-live/"&gt;Max for Live&lt;/a&gt; to read
the data from the headset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to Zvika Markfeld and Saron Paz from &lt;a href="http://forrealteam.com/"&gt;ForReal
Team&lt;/a&gt;, the exhibition curators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A screen capture of MusiGali Ableton Live set:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="youtube youtube-16x9"&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aXbvVGCQ5wY" allowfullscreen seamless frameBorder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Projects"></category></entry><entry><title>A collaborative web synth</title><link href="/projects/a-collaborative-web-synth" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-01-10T23:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-15T00:24:10+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Leverstone</name></author><id>tag:None,2016-01-10:/projects/a-collaborative-web-synth</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Experimenting the Web-Audio API&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My experiments with the &lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/Web_Audio_API"&gt;Web-Audio
API&lt;/a&gt;,
creating a collaborative synthesizer for the web. Using websockets to
communicate between browsers, several players can play the keyboard
simultaneously. The project is only a demo, but it clearly demonstrate
the possibilities that modern web technologies have to offer for
interactive music systems.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Projects"></category></entry><entry><title>Xteams!</title><link href="/projects/xteams" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-12-31T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-15T00:24:10+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Leverstone</name></author><id>tag:None,2015-12-31:/projects/xteams</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Create teams automatically based on discrete scores of the players&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;You want to create teams, but:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can one create teams when Dana doesn't want to play with Haim,
    who must play with Jacob but not with Yossi... You've got the
    idea.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No one will ever want to help in creating teams as he may end up
    insulting a not-so-good player by choosing him last.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maybe you have too many players around for one game, but just enough
    for a tournament of 4 teams.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xteams aim to solve these issues with one goal in mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create teams automatically based on discrete scores of the players&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using Xteams, group managers can give scores to players in the
management panel. Players of the group can't access this panel but can
see the list of players, mark which of them arrived to the game and
create teams easily.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Projects"></category></entry><entry><title>dbdapy</title><link href="/projects/dbdapy" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-17T22:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-03-15T00:24:10+00:00</updated><author><name>Tom Leverstone</name></author><id>tag:None,2016-10-17:/projects/dbdapy</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;"Doing Bayesian Data Analysis" in python&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Python solutions to the exercises of Doing Bayesian Data Analysis, 2nd
Edition, by J. L. Kruschke, using
&lt;a href="https://github.com/pymc-devs/pymc3"&gt;pymc3&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Projects"></category></entry></feed>